A Guide to the American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) records FA079
Rockefeller Archive Center
- American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) photographs, 1946-1968, n.d.; 1027; 6.2 Cubic Feet 19 boxes.
  - Brazil, 2
    - CBR, Agriculture, Silo Pictures, Prints: 16 (Box 4, Folder 110)
      118. One of ten 200 ton silos of Sec. of Agr. Renato Costa Laina (?) being filled. 119. 60 ton silo filled and covered with earth. 120. 170 ton silo of Sr. Dario Meireles (?) producer of Grade A milk from herd of pure blooded Holsteins. He integrates dairying with coffee farming. 121. 160 ton trench silo of Sr. Dario Meireles just filled - twin silo to the empty one. 122. The small farmer usually excavates his trench silo with a scrape drawn by a team of mules. 123. 90% of trench silos in Brazil are not lined. But a lining with a brick placed flat against the sides adds to resistance to rains and life in the silo. 124. Mouth of 250 ton silo of SASA. 125. No caption. 126. Finishing the trench silo. 127. No caption. 128. The open end of this trench silo on a Sao Paulo fazenda is closed with planks when filled and the silage covered with earth during the process of fermentation. 129. Only two days were needed to construct a 125-ton trench silo on this Sao Paulo fazenda using Ford tractor and scraper. 130. 250 trench silo of SASA at Jacaresinho, Panama. 131. Work is underway on a trench silo designed to store the surplus rainy season forage, so that the cattle of the state of Lara may be assured of a cheap, year-round food supply, and the milk production of the area, which has fluctuated greatly from season to season, may be stabilized. 132. A completed 70-ton trench silo at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro. AIA agronomist Marcos Pereira, lower left, discusses the subject with the farm superintendent, while Willard Orcutt, Jr., a Brazilian of American parentage who is assisting Pereira, stands atop the trench silo. 133. Silage is packed down during process of filling a 65-ton trench silo on a farm at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, where AIA is introducing modern and economical farm practices.
    - CBR, Gardening, Prints: 23 (Box 4, Folder 111)
      1. Some of the children who maintain their own individual gardens in the big plot at the fazenda of Mr. Alciro Meirelles. 2. Visitors to the exposition look over the garden planted and maintained by members of the boys' and girls' clubs at the fazenda of Mr. Alciro Meirelles, one of the farmers cooperating in the AIA program. Each child cares for his own plot of ground. 3. Members of a women's club at Fazenda Retriro Grande learning knitting under Senhorita Joana Soares, AIA home economics specialist. 4. Nurse Nona Rosalys Teizeira instructing members of women's club. 5. Members of garden club and hybrid corn club at Rio Clarinho rural school. 6. Members of garden club and hybrid corn club at Rio Clarinho rural school. 7. Brazilian home economist gives sewing instruction to farmers' wives and daughters of Santa Rita. 8. Brazilian home economist gives sewing instruction to farmers' wives and daughters of Santa Rita. 9. A nearly ready garden plot at the Fazenda Itatiaia, to be worked by members of AIA's Boys and Girls Clubs, in the Municipality of Santa Rita do Passa Quatro. Alciro Meirelles, owner of fazenda, stands in one corner. AIA agronomist Marcos Pereira designed the layout and the irrigation ditches. 10. AIA agronomist Marcos Pereira instructs a member of one of the Boys and Girls Clubs at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro in preparing a section of the club garden at Fazenda Itatiaia. 11. Pupils of the Fazenda Monte Alegre school exhibit the seedlings they have just received from AIA's agronomist, Marcos Pereira. 12. AIA agronomist at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, Marcos Pereira, distributes seedlings to the boys of the rural school at the Fazenda Monte Alegre. 13. School building at Estrella, Santa Rita do Passa Quatro; one room currently is being used as school; will house AIA work headquarters for young people's clubs, etc. 14. Production of broccoli seed in nursery. 15. Seed production in nursery. 16. Corner of nursery showing seed production - sweet corn and 17. Corner of nursery showing plants being produced for distribution. 18. Corner of nursery showing blocks of plants for seed production. 19. A section of one of the two AIA vegetable and flower gardens at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro. Between 20,000 and 30,000 seedlings are distributed each month in the municipality, from the two gardens. 20. 2/14/49. Community garden in Santa Rita, Brazil; part of AIA program to promote home gardens and orchards. Pipe in center is from a hydraulicram which automatically lifts water. 21. 2/14/49. Community garden in Santa Rita, Brazil; part of AIA program to promote home gardens and orchards. Pipe in center is from a hydraulicram which automatically lifts water. 22. Vegetable seedbed nursery in Santa Rita do Passa Quatro by AIA, for distribution among rural families. Because of the slope of the land, embankments have been constructed, 6/49. 23. A section of one of the two AIA vegetable and flower gardens at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro. Between 20,000 and 30,000 seedlings are distributed each month in the municipality, from the two gardens.
    - CBR, General, 1950 Exposition, Prints: 18 (Box 5, Folder 112)
      1. - 18. No caption.
    - CBR, General, Miscellaneous, Prints: 24 (Box 5, Folder 113)
      19. - 42. No caption.
    - CBR, General, Reports, 12/1950, Prints: 9 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      43. Drawing that shows the express highway of Tiete proposal to be executed along the river. 44. Access road to the Triborough Bridge. 45. The "Southern Parkway" in Queens. A typical artery with six lanes of traffic. 46. Water treatment station in New York, with service to adjoining local park. 47. Express highway that shows the central lane for future fast transit, and the station in the bridge. 48. Jones Beach State Park. North Atlantic Ocean, an hour car ride from New York, situated at a similar distance from Santos to Sao Paulo. 49. Station garage constructed for the Triborough Bridge & Tunnel Authority situated at the entrance to the Battery-Brooklyn tunnel at the south end of Manhattan. 50. Model of modern omnibus with the capacity of 135 passengers, whose immediate purchase is recommended (?). 51. Bus terminal at new ferry boat station on Staten Island, New York.
    - CBR, Nutrition, Mobile Health Unit, Prints: 9 (Box 5, Folder 115)
      1. The "country doctor" of the rural health service, Dr. Campo Bello, was born on a fazenda in the community. He knows the people and their problems and they have confidence in him. Here he examines a farm women, one of many served by the mobile clinic. 2. Children of the rural school at the Fazenda Monte Alegre, municipality of Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, leave their class-room on arrival of the State Health Department truck bringing them seedlings for their home gardens. They are taught how to plant and raise vegetables and flowers by the agronomist of AIA. May 1950 3. AIA Exposition at Santa Rita, August 1950- Dr. Reginaldo Alves dos Santos, dentist of the State Public Health Service, performs an extraction. Teeth have been so badly neglected among Santa Rita's poorer rural residents that, at the beginning of his work, Dr. Reginaldo had no time to do anything put pull the worst ones. Total extractions in his first three weeks' work: 334 4. Dr. Miguel Bello, State health physician, assigned to cooperate in the AIA program at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, takes the blood pressure of a farmwife at the Fazenda Monte Alegre. The woman, who had had no medical treatment for a long time, was found to be in a serious condition. 5. The ambulatory clinic in which the State Health Service and AIA cooperate maintains regular scheduled services at 14 outposts in the muncipio handling about 100 clients per day. Vaccinations, campaigns against hookworms and other internal parasites, rural hygiene and preventive medicines are emphasized. 6. AIA nurse, Miss Joana Soares, records information about a woman patient who is to be examined by Dr. Miguel Bello, at the Fazenda Monte Alegre, while school children await their turn. May 1950 7. Jan 49, Brazil (AIA) School building at Ibo, Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, formerly a church; will be future health center under AIA program. 8. Public health nurse settlers kitchen: ouring weekly visits she gives advice on problems of feeding, health, going to the homes to find out the problems of the people. AIA, Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, Brazil June 1949 9. Jan 49, Brazil (AIA) School building at Ibo, Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, formerly a church; will be future health center under AIA program.
    - EMA, Bebedouro, Prints: 7 (Box 5, Folder 116)
      1. Discing machine drawn by light diesel tractor; discing equipment used on newly cleared areas. 2. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Land being seeded with Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 3. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Machinery used to seed corn. 4. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Machinery used to seed corn. 5. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Business end of TD-18 tractor. Isaacson Klearing dozer with detachable teeth, elevator control. 6. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. EMA Technical Director, Carl Schneider, explaining principle of terracing equipment used in soil conservation work. Terracing the land helps prevent soil erosion, keeps rain from washing away topsoil. 7. Land clearing operation in Bebedouro, Brazil, by EMA, farm mechanization company and affiliate of IBEC of which Nelson A. Rockefeller is president.
    - EMA, Jacarezinho, Prints: 31 (Box 5, Folder 117)
      8. Joao Toledo (left), manager, Jacarezinho EMA unit; Dr. Oscar Thompson, Commercial Manager EMA. 9. EMA, Jacarezinho, Brazil. 6:30 am morning line at Usina Jacarezinho. EMA's big clearing, stumping and plowing job keeps machines and crews in motion around the clock. After the night shift, tractors move to field base for cleaning, lubrication, fueling, and inspection. 10. Jacarezinho, Parana, 1/20/1949. EMA heavy duty tractor pushes fallen brush into windows at Usina Jacarezinho sugar plantation. 11. EMA. Intricate tree felling operation performed by Eliseo Alves de Lima, qualified after less than two months training by EMA, Jacarezinho. 12. Oscar Thompson, former commercial manager of EMA, now manager of a larger sugar fazenda between Ourinhos and Jacarezinho. 13. EMA. Plowing as well as clearing goes ahead after sundown on sugar plantation between Ourihnos and Jacarezinho. 14. EMA. TD-18 in a clearing operation on a fazenda near Jacarezinho carried out by EMA, an affiliate of the IBEC. 15. EMA. TD-18 in a clearing operation on a fazenda near Jacarezinho carried out by EMA, an affiliate of the IBEC. 16. EMA, Jacarezinho. Next stage of EMA operation at Usina Jacarezinho is plowing. Heavy disc equipment used on newly cleared areas. 17. EMA, Jacarezinho. Bunkhouse at Usina Jacarezinho - temporary home of EMA crew. 18. EMA, Jacarezinho. Worker's bunkhouse, Jacarezinho compound. 19. EMA, Jacarezinho. Stockroom control. Records are kept here of all parts used in Jacarezinho unit operations. 20. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building. 21. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building, interior. Heavy machine installations stored in room, background. 22. EMA, Jacarezinho. Well water for tractor cooling system. 23. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 24. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 25. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 26. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 27. EMA, Jacarezinho. EMA tractor drivers and maintenance crew at Usina Jacarezinho field base. 28. EMA, Jacarezinho. Farmall light tractor with harvester-binder. 29. EMA, Jacarezinho. Fuel drums here bear distinctive EMA markings and colors. 30. EMA, Jacarezinho. Fuel deposit. 31. EMA, Jacarezinho. Precision instruments, valuable small parts stored in this building. 32. EMA, Jacarezinho. Unit office. Manager Joao Toledo, right. 33. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building, an old barn remodeled. 34. EMA, Jacarezinho, Brazil. 6:30 am morning line at Usina Jacarezinho. EMA's big clearing, stumping and plowing job keeps machines and crews in motion around the clock. After the night shift, tractors move to field base for cleaning, lubrication, fueling, and inspection. 35. EMA, Jacarezinho. Cleaning platform for trucks and tractors; region's deep mud and heavy dust make frequent, complete washing necessary routine. 36. EMA, Jacarezinho. Land being seeded with Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 37. Joao Toldeo, with AH Vandenberg Jr., with map showing area in which EMA operates; Joao Toledo, former manager of EMA's Jacarezinho unit, is now assistant to Carl Schneider, EMA manager. 38. EMA, Jacarezinho. Joao Toldeo, Brazilian assistant to EMA's manager; formerly was manager of the Jacarezinho unit.
    - EMA, Miscellaneous, Prints: 15 (Box 5, Folder 118)
      39. 1,000,000-bushel grain elevator in the state of Sao Paulo, Brazil, serves centers of consumption and exportation in Ourinhos area. 40. Oscar Thompson, Commercial Mgr. of EMA instructing Brazilian tractor driver on his first day of work. International Harvester tractor of TD-14 type. 41. An EMA TD-9 tractor with bulldozer filling holes caused by erosion in a pasture near Mococa. 42. Section of a road ruined by erosion to be filled and leveled by EMA machines near Mococa. 43. Detail of machinery used for terracing; EMA has introduced this equipment into Brazil. 44. No caption. 45. No caption. 46. No caption. 47. No caption. 48. No caption. 49. No caption. 50. No caption. 51. No caption. 52. No caption. 53. No caption.
    - HELICO, Prints: 8 (Box 5, Folder 119)
      1. HELICO, Brazil. Helicopters used in dusting operations; taken at Bauru, Brazil, 2/1949. 2. HELICO, Brazil. Bell Aircraft maintenance representative at Bauru, Brazil. 3. - 8. HELICO, Brazil. Helicopters used in dusting operations; taken at Bauru, Brazil.
    - SASA, Prints: 5 (Box 5, Folder 120)
      1. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, with A.H. Vandenberg, Jr. at sorting table. Sorting table permits ear corn to flow past workers well trained in elimination of all ears not suitable for seed. 2. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, center, explains tests of 36 hybrids at Santa Rita to agricultural writer Mario Mazzei. Isidro Zarate, fazenda foreman, right. 3. SASA town headquarters in Jacarezinho. Homero Freitas, SASA manager and office assistant. 4. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, inspecting corn at sorting table, which permits corn to flow past workers well trained in elimination of all ears not suitable for seed. Discarded ears are weighed back to the cooperators (farmers who sell their corn to SASA) and discounted from total of corn received. 5. No caption.
    - SAFAP, Agriculture, Prints: 55 (Box 5, Folder 121)
      1. No caption. 2. Newborn Duroc-Jeresy; ages one and ten days. 1949. 3. Common Sow with pigs. 4. Common Sow with pigs. 5. Excellent yield of Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 6. San Carlos. Entrance to the breeding farm. 7. Field feeding shed for unweaned litters. 8. Farrowing house, showing enclosed yard. 9. Berkshire boar, recently acquired. 10. Berkshire boar, another newcomer. 11. Newborn animal treatment series. 12. Common hog at automatic feeder. 13. New arrival in litter of 15 pure blood Duroc pigs; a SAFAP record. 14. Post natal treatments completed. Duroc-Jersey, first day. 15. Field farrowing house. 16. Farrowing building with kikuio grass pasturage in foreground. 17. Common sow, soon to farrow. 18. Pure Duroc boar, seven months old. 19. Newborn animal treatment series. Tying umbilical cord. 20. Duroc-Jersey sow and six week old offspring. The group has been removed from "Maternidade" to a field shelter. 21. Another view of Maternidade with shelter pen beyond. 22. Center aisle of Maternidade. 23. Maternidade. Pregnant sows are brought to this building a few days before time of delivery and remain there until several days after farrowing. 24. Duroc-Jerseys making most of conveniences of automatic drinking fixture. 25. Detail of Maternidade interior. Each stall is temporary home of new family. 26. Thatch roof makes ideal sun shelter for SAFAP porkers. 27. Self-feeder. Feed is put at top of these boxes and made easily available to stock at the feeding periods. 28. Self-feeders and hog shelter. 29. Butch, prize Duroc-Jersey boar, fathered most of the SAFAP population at Sao Carlos. 30. Several Duroc-Jersey families - pigs at two months - occupy comfortable quarters in field shelter. Young animals are ready for weaning. 31. Clipping needle teeth of newborn animal. Needle teeth impede proper feeding from sow. 32. Vaccinating newborn animal against enteritis. 33. Notching ear of newborn animal for information other than numbering. 34. Notching ear of newborn animal for numbering. 35. Two new additions to SAFAP population. 36. Duroc-Jersey sow and three day old litter. 37. This Duroc-Jersey mother of 15 established a record at Sao Carlos. All members of the family do not appear. 38. Manager Marra displays the success of SAFAP's experiment with Sudan grass. This fodder, imported from Texas, is planted with soy beans (near bottom) and has given exceptional results as an element of diet. 39. Part of equipment in use on Sao Carlo farm. 40. Inspection of newborn litter, day of birth. 41. Main farrowing house; purebred gilts, about 7 months. 42. Feed supplies for SAFAP stock in the growing stage. Hybrid corn with Sudan grass and soy beans between rows; maternity barn in background. 43. Kiln and brick drying yard. Molding huts in background. 44. Farrowing house showing individual stalls. 45. The supply truck, shown here makes daily deliveries of water and fodder to installations in the farm's several sections. 46. Duroc-Jersey pigs, pictures are six months old, in excellent condition. 47. Disc breaking plow, with Ford tractor, part of machine equipment at Capao Bonito. 48. Farm equipment warehouse. This building is equipped with maintenance facilities. 49. Jeep and heavy duty disc plow. 50. Duroc-Jersey making most of conveniences of automatic drinking fixture. 51. Thatch roof makes ideal sun shelter for SAFAP porkers. 52. A new Duroc-Jersey family at home in Maternidade. 53. Butch - still behind his fence. 54. Second farrowing house. 55. Field shelter, automatic feeders, farrowing house in background.
    - SAFAP, Home Improvement, Prints: 6 (Box 5, Folder 122)
      56. SAFAP makes own bricks at CAPAO BONITO in kiln shown here. 57. Central group of buildings. Brick kiln and warehouse, machinery shelter, workers' houses. 58. Main workers' house. 59. Overseer's house. 60. Recently constructed duplex home for farm workers. 61. Dr. Ozanam Marra, SAFAP manager at Sao Carlo, in front of home reconstructed from one of the original barns. This house is equipped with electricity, running water and convenience unusual to similar housing in the countryside surrounding Sao Carlos.
    - SAFAP, Miscellaneous, Prints: 3 (Box 5, Folder 123)
      62. General view of SAFAP property looking from farm headquarters. 63. General view of farm headquarters - left to right: new duplex home for workers, well shelter, farm warehouse, old worker's quarters, manager's home. 64. General view of Sao Carlo farm; new duplex home for workers at left, farm warehouse in center, manager's home at right.
    - SAPS, Administration, Prints: 13 (Box 5, Folder 124)
      1. Representatives of AIA visit the mission of the American Franciscan Conventuals at Rua Caetano Martins 42, Rio de Janeiro, and are greeted by Father Julius d'Esutachio, of Perth Amboy, NJ. L to R: Father Julius, Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Dr. John B. Griffing, James Maddox, Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. 2. At the SAPS kindergarten in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro, the children practice counting by placing blocks on a table, under the guidance of Senhorita Rocilda Pimentel. Watching them are Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in Brazil; James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Mrs. Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 3. Descending the "Morro de Kerosene" by a long flight of steps, a visiting party stops to rest. L to R: Father Julius d'Esutachio, of Perth Amboy, NJ, James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. 4. SAPS boy's club members from Kerosene Hill, Rio de Janeiro (l to r) Abel de S Souza Lopes and Jose Gregorio de Olegario, doing handicraft painting at the SAPS headquarters in Rio de Janeiro, while their teacher, Senhorita Cirene Alexandrino Barreto, explains their work to (l to r) Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in Brazil; Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), and Mrs. Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 5. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 6. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 7. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 8. James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), and Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio. 9. Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in charge of training home visitors for SAPS, Julius d'Esutachio, Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil, and James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY). 10. Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar, passing along the narrow path on kerosene Hill flanked by poor shacks. 11. Climbing the Morro do Kerosene in Rio de Janeiro to visit a school and clubhouse operated by the American Franciscan Conventuals are (l to r) Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar, and Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. Three hill residents are passing them on the steep climb. 12. Mrs. Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. Her husband, Major Umberto Peregrino, is director general of the organization. In the photo, behind Mrs. Peregrino, are Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil, and James Maddox, assistant director of AIA. 13. Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in Brazil; James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), talk with a house wife in the "favela" at Praia do Pinto (Pinto Beach), Leblon.
    - SAPS, Crafts, Prints: 12 (Box 5, Folder 125)